OFEIMUN MATHIAS

mathiasolumese@gmail.com (904) 194-0612 Lagos

Summary

Highly focused and multifaceted Software developer experienced working with React and Next framework also in working with UX/UI Product designers in structuring and designing web pages, products, also collaborate with backend developers in ensuring technical feasibility and fetching data from the backend with a strong client satisfaction record.

Experience

Frontend React Developer

UNIGIG (University Projec) • Lagos, Nigeria

08/2022 - Present

Developed, maintained, troubleshoot, enhanced and documented software products and components developed in relation to the requirements and detailed UI & UX design from the figma.

Collaborated with team members especially backend developers to consume REST API'S to bring all functionalities to the client side. I also tested the site for usability and fixing any bugs.

I helped developed and designed the Student, Admin, Lecturer, section, Registration Officer, Exam Officer, Parent section, HOD sections e.t.c.

I helped to implement several functionalities from the backend using API'S like user authentication for students using Ison Web Tokens.

I created a feature for uploading, saving, editing and retrieving student's information and other users profile.

I Created a dashboard to handle various users. I developed the search functionality to help students find their results with their Academic Year.

Front End Developer (Contract)

Support Plug • Lagos, Nigeria

06/2022 - Present

Designing and developing scalable, robust, testable, efficient, and easily maintainable code.

I developed and worked with other developers to help manage some Client's websites and Web Applications Using various tools and languages of the web like HTML5,CSS3,JAVASCRIPT,REACT, WORDPRESS,REDUX,GIT COMMANDS etc.I also manage the files and databases on Cpanel.

Front End Developer

Forbes Digits • Lagos, Nigeria

02/2022 - 06/2022

Improved Forbes web development structures/systems by adding new features and infrastructure to enhance customers' experience.

I handled the Sales landing page for Forbes digits which brough more conversions and subscribers specifically about 1200 clicks per page and around 7% conversions for a chat on WhatsApp or telegram response. Code restructuring, explicit and well-formatted reusable codes and libraries.

Developing and debugging responsive web applications and websites.

Software Developer

Ten Pharmacy and Stores • Lagos, Nigeria

11/2019 - 01/2020

Developed, maintained, troubleshoot, enhanced and documented software products and components developed in relation to the requirements and detailed design.

Collaborated with team members and stakeholders to communicate with other services through the event and messaging platforms and also tested the site for usability and fixing any bugs.

Created a Feedback form for to allowing site users to contact the Pharmacist for health consultation.

Skills

Javascript, Software development, CSS, Time Management, Teamwork, Team Leader, Html5, cross-browser compatibility, Analysis Skills, Problem solving skill

Education

O'level

Command Day Secondary School • Oshodi Lagos, Nigeria Senior School Certificate Examination

06/2018

Courses and Certifications

Linkedin Learning Software Development Training Courses in partnership with RBC future paid Canadian Programme. (2019-present)

Alx-Udacity Software and Web Development Foundations Training.

Center for Entrepreneurship development (CED) (2 months) Web dev Program at University of Benin. (Oct 2021)

Core Competence

HTML

CSS

Javascript

Typescript

Bootstrap

Tailwind CSS

React and Next js frameworks

Redux

Rest API'S

Firebase

Wordpress

Elementor

Projects and Achievements

2022 An Ecommerce Web App For sale of Books using Next js, Next js Auth, React,

React Hooks, Context API, Sanity, Tailwind Css, Paystack, Firebase, Css modules

Project at https://ecommerces-seven.vercel.app/

2022 | My recent role as a frontend developer for Forbes digits website

Forbes Digits offers consultation services and sale of digital courses online

Project at https://forbesdigits.com/

2019 - 2020 | Web developer and designer at Ten pharmacy and stores in Lagos.

Worked as site maintenance and Website Administrator.

Project the website at https://tenpharmacyandstores.shop

2022 | Created a Web Application for a client that specializes in Offering Emcee services for Traditional Weddings and Other Event services. Project at https://meetmctina.netlify.app/

2022 | Created an App that has User Authentication that enables people to create meetings, allow people to register, Login and check in to pick random users for an event. It also an Admin function as well.

Project at https://react-spas-e15f6.firebaseapp.com/

2022 | Created a User Info Authentication form to sign up users and collect information from them with a contact form using react and firebase Firebase project at https://web-chats.netlify.app/

2022 | Created a chatting web Application to aid communication using react Firebase Project at https://react-grid-dashboard-e880e.web.app/

2021 Developed a catering website for a cake business

Project at https://3ddesertcakes.shop/ front end built with Bootstrap.

2020 | An Educational website to help Nigerians have access to information and educational materials with exams past questions such as

SAT, IELTS, TOEFL, JAMB, WAEC.

Project at http://mattcofreebooksandupdates.com front end built with Bootstrap

2021 - present | freelancer worked a site for students to have access to past questions and answers for local and international exams for free with React.js framework.

Project at https://getpastquestionsandanswers.online/

2022 | Created a Todo App with react and firebase

Project at https://todoapp-fa474.web.app/

Professional profiles

GitHub

https://www.github.com/Mattcopedia

Work Portfolio link

https://my-portfolio-three-lime.vercel.app

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ofeimun-mathias-763a15200

Reference

On Request